A Finding Aid to the Walter Pach Papers, 1857-1980, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1899-circa 1950s; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Box 3-5
  - Writings by Pach, 1899-circa 1950s; 3.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Manuscripts and Typescripts, circa 1920-circa 1950s; 3.1.2; Archival Resource Key
      - "The Art Museum in America," Draft 3, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29-34)
        The Museum and the Public
        The Museum of the New World
        Supplement: A List of Museums of Art in the United States
      - "The Art Museum in America," Draft 4, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35-40)
        Preface and Acknowledgements
        Introduction
        Chapter 1: On Art Museums
        Chapter 4: The Achievement
        Chapter 5: Problems and Theories and The Problem of the American Artist
        Chapter 5: The Museum and the Public
        Chapter 6: The Museum of the New World
        Supplement
      - "The Art Museum in America," Fragments, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
        Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 3
      - "The Century of Grace," Published in The Nation, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - "The Child in the Work of Diego Rivera", circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - "The Choice of Artists in American Art", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - "The Collection of John Quinn, Part One: The Collector", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - "The Makers of Modern Art", circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46-48)
      - "The Oldest American University", circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - "The Outlook for Modern Art," Published in Parnassus, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - "The Shilling Fund", circa 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - "Unknown Aspects of Mexican Painting", circa 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "Van Gogh's Letters to Anton Van Rappard" Introduction, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - "Variations in Consciousness (or Knowledge) During the Work of the Artist", circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - "Vincent Van Gogh", circa 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - "Vincent Van Gogh 1853-1890", 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
      - "Whitney Museum Symposium", circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Oversized, "The Art Museum in America", circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
        Oversized material scanned with Box 4, Folder 41
    - School Writings, 1899-1912; 3.1.3; Archival Resource Key
      "Lectures on Aesthetics" is Pach's bound manuscript entitled "A Course of Lectures on Aesthetics as Delivered by Professor Solomon Woolf and Doctor Leigh Hunt, Before the Senior Class, and as Noted by Walter Pach of Section Five."
      - "Lectures on Aethsetics", circa 1903; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - School Essays, 1899-1902; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - School Notes, Biology Notebook, CCNY, 1903; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - School Notes, "Lycee Charlemagne - Un Cours de Bonheur. L'Oeuvre de M. Henry Marx" Notebook 1, 1911-1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - School Notes, "Lycee Charlemagne - Un Cours de Bonheur. L'Oeuvre de M. Henry Marx" Notebook 2, 1911-1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Fragments, Memos and Notes, circa 1910-circa 1950; 3.1.4; Archival Resource Key
      Series includes bibliographic citations, price lists, notes on paintings, lists of people to see, notes for a report to Henry Allen Moe, expenses, notes from readings, recipes for gesso and glue, lists of plates for Faure's History of Art; and research notes on Delacroix, Renoir, and Courbet.
      Also found is a set of index cards of artwork arranged A-Z by artist.
      - Fragments, Memos and Notes, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17-21)
      - Index Cards of Artwork, A-J by Artist, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Index Cards of Artwork, K-Z by Artist, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Lists, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1910-circa 1950s; 3.2; Archival Resource Key
    Series has been scanned in entirety.
    Series includes typescripts and handwritten copies of poems, chapters of books, articles, and prose by Apollinaire, Baudelaire, Faure, Le Roy, Mallarmé, Rouault, Villon, and others.
    - Authors: Appollinaire-Faure, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
      Apollinaire, Guillaume, "The Book of Beasts," 1911
      Baudelaire, Charles, "Les Flerus du Mal"
      Collier, John, "The Role of Evaluation in Social Research," circa 1953
      Cuesta, J., "Song to a Funeral God"
      Faure, Elie, "History of Art: Modern Art, chapter 3"
    - Authors: Haigh-Villon, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Haigh, Frances S. and Hovey, Angelica V. R., "Walter Pach"
      Le Roy, Jean, "Printemps"
      Mallarme, Stephane, "Vers et Prose"
      Roualt, Georges, "A Little Poem in Popular Style Addressed to an American Who Loves France"
      Villon, Jacques, "Expose Preliminaire sur la Peinture, Le Peinture Dans la Societe Moderne," UNESCO International Conference of Artists, 1952
      Villon, Jacques, "Les Poilus" ("The Shaggy Men")
    - Authors: Unidentified, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Authors: Various, Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
- Diaries and Journals, 1903-circa 1950s; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 5 Folders Box 5
  Of particular note is a travel diary, dated 1903-1904, recording Pach's trips to Europe with William Merritt Chase's class. The entries include reflections on life abroad, fellow classmates Morton Livingston Schamberg and Charles Sheeler, Pach's early interest in Japonisme and active collecting of Japanese art, including prints by master ukiyo-e artists Hokusai and Hiroshige, and the purchase in Holland of a Manga book (an artist's instructional manual) by Hokusai.
  Also included here is a folder of addresses recording Pach's contacts in Mexico in 1942-1943 and an address book with journal entries made during a UNESCO Congress of Critics in Paris, circa 1948.
  A "Shelley Birthday Book" notes birthdays of Pach family members and friends.
  - Addresses and Diary, UNESCO Congress of Critics in Paris, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Addresses, "Mexico 1942-1943", Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Journal, 1903-1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Journal, Loose Pages, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - "Shelley Birthday Book", circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Business Records, circa 1913-circa 1960s; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 5-6
  Of particular note in this series are two record books: one in which Pach recorded sales for the Armory Show, New York beginning February 18th and ending March 15, 1913, listing the person purchasing each picture and the amount paid, and "signed off" with the inscription "OK" and the initials "JM," presumably Jerome Myers; the second in which Pach recorded sales for the Armory Show in Boston and Chicago beginning March 23 and ending April 30, 1913, also signed off by "JM."
  Other items of note include an "agenda" book from 1930-1932 which contains lists of paintings owned and sold by Pach in addition to what appears to be an inventory of his belongings, including contents of the Pach apartment; and two record books containing a "record of pictures, writings and lectures," notes on "pictures sold, exchanged or presented," and a list of "places where I have lectured." The books cover the years 1903-1950s.
  One folder contains consignment lists for Pach's paintings and etchings at Kraushaar Galleries and E. Weyhe in 1934.
  A record book belonging to Nikifora Pach contains notes on loans and sales of pictures in the late 1950s, in addition to enclosures documenting loan and consignment transactions with Zabriskie Gallery, the Museum of Modern Art, and others in the early 1960s. Also found is a photocopy of a list of paintings belonging to Pach and given to Nikifora Pach in the 1950s.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. Routine personal business records including life and medical insurance records, property and tax records and financial and legal papers relating to Raymond Pach, have not been scanned.
  - Account Books, 1930-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - "Agenda" Book Listing Paintings Owned and Sold by Pach, 1930-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Bank Statements and Receipts, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Consignment Lists, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Financial and Legal Papers, Magda and Raymond Pach, 1939-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Income Tax Records, 1946-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Insurance, Life and Medical, 1924-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Insurance, Property, 1937-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Investment Records, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Library of Congress Cards and Copyright Certificates, circa 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - List of Books, circa 1930s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Lists of Paintings by/belonging to Pach Given to Nikifora Pach (photocopies), 1951-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Medical Expenses/Records, 1948-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Notebook Recording Sales at the Armory Show, New York, 1913 February-March; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Notebook Recording Sales at the Armory Show, Boston, Chicago, 1913 March-April; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Property Records, 1930s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Record Book of Nikifora Pach, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Records of Pictures Sold, Lectures and Publications, circa 1903-circa 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Printed Material, circa 1900-1977; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 1.3 Linear feet Box 6-7, 9
  Printed material relating to Pach and others, includes rare exhibition announcements and catalogs such as a 1913 Boston Armory Show catalog annotated with prices, printed articles by Pach and about him including book reviews of his work, reproductions of artwork including postcards from the 1913 Armory Show, news clippings and miscellany.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of duplicates and the complete texts of some publications for which only the cover and relevant pages have been scanned.
  6.1: Pach Printed Material, 1907-1959
  6.2: Other Printed Material, circa 1900-1977
  - Pach Printed Material, 1907-1959; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    Printed material by Pach includes announcements and exhibition catalogs for Pach's solo and group exhibitions, including a a 1913 annotated Boston Armory Show catalog. Also found are two booklets written by Pach and published on the occasion of the Armory Show: A Sculptor's Architecture, and Odilon Redon.
    Also found here is an almost complete collection of Pach's published articles in the form of the pages from the journals, magazines, and newspapers in which they appeared, including Scribner's Magazine, Dial, Shadowland, Parnassus, and 35 columns writtten for The Freeman between 1920 and 1924.
    - About Pach, 1910-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Catalog, Armory Show, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Group Exhibitions, 1907-1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Group Exhibitions, 1915-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Group Exhibitions, circa 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Solo Exhibitions, 1925-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Solo Exhibitions, 1931-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Solo Exhibitions, 1936-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Lecture Announcements, Pach, 1906-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Published Writings by Pach, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
      - Armory Show, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1907-1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1911-1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1913-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1920-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1926-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1932-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1952-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1916-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Reviews of Books by Pach, 1924-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Other Printed Material, circa 1900-1977; 6.2; Archival Resource Key
    The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of duplicates and the full text of certain publications for which only the cover and relevant pages have been scanned.
    Other printed material includes announcements and exhibition catalogs for artists other than Pach as well as for a 1937 Pach Brothers exhibition "American Personalities Through Seven Decades," news clippings on subjects of apparent interest to Pach, postcards from the Armory Show and other reproductions of artwork.
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, circa 1907-1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1911-1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1913-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1919-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1922-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, circa 1930-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1943-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Pach Brothers, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1890s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35-36)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 4
    - News Clippings, General, circa 1900-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 37)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 5
    - News Clippings, General, circa 1907-1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - News Clippings, General, 1914-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - News Clippings, General, 1966-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Postcards, Armory Show, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Postcards of Artwork, circa 1910-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1920-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9 Folder 6
    - Travel Booklets, circa 1900-circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Oversized, Miscellaneous, circa 1890s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 6, Folder 36
    - Oversized, News Clippings, General, circa 1900-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 6, Folder 37
    - Oversized Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1920-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 3
- Scrapbooks, circa 1890-circa 1940s; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 7, 9
  Scrapbooks include a dismantled scrapbook of reviews and original letters relating to Pach's book Ananias or the False Artist, published in 1928. Also housed here is a scrapbook primarily documenting Pach's activities during the 1920s which included his first one-man show at the Brummer Gallery in New York City and the publication of his books Masters of Modern Art and Raymond Duchamp-Villon. The scrapbook contains news clippings with press reviews of Pach's work.
  A scrapbook of musical and theatrical events and programs includes a program for a 1917 Neighorhood Playhouse production of a Wallace Stevens's play, Bowl, Cat and Broomstick, for which Pach designed the sets. Also found is a guestbook from an unidentified event.
  - Ananias or the Bad Artist, Contents of Scrapbook, 1928-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
  - Ananias or the Bad Artist, Additional News Clippings, 1928-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Guest Book of Unidentified Event, circa 1920s-circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 7
  - Scrapbook of the 1920s, circa 1913-1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 8
  - Scrapbook of Musical and Theatrical Events and Programs, circa 1890-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Guest Book of Unidentified Event, circa 1920s-circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 9
  - Oversized Scrapbook of the 1920s, circa 1913-1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 10
- Artwork, circa 1860-circa 1950s; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 7, 10
  This series consists of a small group of loose drawings and three early sketchbooks by Pach, plus several drawings by unidentified artists. Also included are two print portfolios published in 1947 by the Laurel Gallery, New York City; one includes an essay by Pach and the other an etching by Pach. These portfolios include hand-pulled prints by artists such as Milton Avery, Reginald Marsh, and Joan Miro.
  - By Pach, Drawings, circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - By Pach, Sketchbooks, circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - By Pach and Others, Laurel Gallery Portfolios, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 1
  - By Others, Miniature Portrait of Frances Wise (Pach's mother), circa 1860s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - By Others, Unidentified Artists, circa 1920s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Oversized By Pach and Others, Laurel Gallery Portfolios, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 16
- Photographs, 1857-1959; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Box 7-8, 10
  This series includes photographs of Pach, his family, and artists/friends, as well as group pictures of William Merritt Chase's class, Robert Henri's class at the New York School of Art, circa 1904, and others. There are also photographs of works of art by Pach and others. Of special interest is a group of photographs of mural projects in Mexico by José Clemente Orozco and Diego Rivera.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  9.1: Photographs of People and Places, 1857-1959
  9.2: Photographs of Artwork, circa 1907-circa 1950s
  - Photographs of People and Places, 1857-1959; 9.1; Archival Resource Key
    This series has been scanned in entirety with the exception of negatives and duplicates.
    This series includes photographs of Pach from boyhood to the 1950s, including portraits, photos with family members, in his studio and apartment, in group photos and with artists and friends, including Florence Arquin and Diego Rivera. Included is a series of photos by Hansel Mieth of Pach in his studio and with Magda Pach in their home listening to Raymond Pach playing the piano.
    Photos of others include the following artists and friends: Edith Bell, William Merritt Chase, Raymond Duchamp-Villon, Thomas Eakins, Arthur B. Frost, Jr., Carl Hauser, Robert Henri, Inna Khabroff, Susan McDonnel, Moriye Ogihara, Pablo Picasso, Eda Puckhaber, and General and Mrs. Webb.
    Also of note is a collection of photographs of Pach's apartment, art collection and studio, circa 1959.
    - Of Pach, Portraits, circa 1900-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 2
    - Of Pach, Portraits (Duplicates and Negatives), circa 1900-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Of Pach and Pach Family, circa 1880-1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
    - Of Pach and Pach Family-Daguerrotype of Pach's Mother and Grandparents, 1857; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Of Pach and Pach Family, Magda Pach, circa 1890-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Of Pach and Pach Family, Raymond Pach and Others, circa 1930-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Of Pach with Florence Arquin and Diego Rivera, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Of Pach and Groups Pictures of Artists/Friends, circa 1904-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Of Pach and Others, Unidentified, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Of Others, Artists and Friends, circa 1870-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
    - Of Others, Group of Artists by Durand-Ruel, circa 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Of Others, William Merritt Chase European Summer School, Madrid, Spain?, circa 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Of Others, William Merritt Chase European Summer School, Madrid, Spain?, circa 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Of Others, Mexican Dancers, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Of Others, Unidentified, circa 1900-circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Of Buildings/Engineering Projects, 1919-1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Of a House, Inscribed "From Ruth and Arthur", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Of Installations, Society of Independent Artists, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Of Pach Apartment, Art Collection and Studio, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 39-41)
    - Of Pach Apartment, Art Collection and Studio, Negatives and Duplicates, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Of Pach House, Brewster, NY, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Of Still Life signed by Sidney Waintraub, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Oversized of Pach, Portraits, circa 1900-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 7 Folder 19